Lurelle Guild Papers
Lurelle Guild Papers
1931-1968
Guild, Lurelle Van Arsdale, 1898-1985
121.0 linear ft., 30.0 cubic ft.
Papers of the American industrial designer, painter. Correspondence on designs and advertising; financial records including bank statements and bills; shop drawings, plans and blueprints for projects; photographs of design work; printed material; and memorabilia including models for various items designed by Guild.
149026
Biographical History
Lurelle Van Arsdale Guild, born in Syracuse, New York, was an American architect and prolific industrial designer. Shortly after graduating from Syracuse University in 1920, he and his wife relocated to New York City and Guild started his own business, Lurelle Guild Associates, to design and market home furnishings and decorative arts. The company, which became hugely successful, produced designs, drawings, models, prototypes, and worked with manufacturers on product development and marketing. Guild's usual method was to invent or develop the new product, patent it, and then assign the patent to the manufacturer, charging a fee and royalties. Guild also played an active role in product development and marketing: placing samples of his products in retail shops, surveying potential customers, even trucking refrigerators into a local neighborhood in order to poll the residents.
[Photo at right: Aluminum and glass Kensington Ware bowl, ca. 1934]
Guild is particularly known for his long relationship with Alcoa. In the early 1930s Alcoa, actively searching for new market opportunities beyond utilitarian cookware, hired Guild to design a giftware line for them. "Kensington Ware," as it was known, debuted in 1934 and featured Art Deco items in five categories: table and service, decorative pieces, drinking glasses and accessories/barware, smoker's articles, and desk accessories. In the fall of 1935, Alcoa began advertising Kensington Ware in various popular and women's magazines, including Vogue, Atlantic Monthly, Harper's Magazine, House and Garden, Country Life, and Time. Kensington Ware sold very well and is still collected today. Guild continued to design new products for the Kensington giftware line until it was discontinued soon after World War II.
Lurelle Guild was also a capable interior designer. He designed the Kensington showroom in Rockefeller Center in New York City and the permanent "museum" at Alcoa's New York offices, which displayed individual products as works of art on modern display tables of extruded aluminum, skillfully lit.
In 1947, Alcoa again looked to Guild, this time to design hardware/aluminum furniture. Guild modern designs included chairs, tables, consoles, vanity desks, bed headboards, night stands, chests and a glazed cabinet. Alcoa sold over 400,000 Kensington and Wear-Ever chairs before discontinuing the line in 1952.
In addition to Alcoa, Guild's client list grew to encompass many of the major manufacturers of the day: Aluminum Cooking Utensil Company, Allied Chemical, American Airlines, American Locomotive, Burgess Battery Company, Philip Carey Manufacturing, Chase Brass and Copper, Colgate Palmolive, Congoleum, Corning Glass Works, E.I. DuPont, General Foods, Gulf Oil, IBM, International Silver, Kensington, Miller Metal, Monsanto, Pitney - Bowes, Pullman Cars, Remington, Revlon, Schick, Servel (Electrolux), Sylvania, Union Carbide, and Westinghouse. He designed a vast range of products, including clocks, dishes, railroad cars, vacuum cleaners, typewriters, and gas stoves. Guild became so well-known that his name and photograph were even used as marketing material.
Guild died in 1985.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The papers of Lurelle Guild consist of eight series. General files contains correspondence with clients regarding product design, development, marketing, advertising, etc. Financial records includes bank statements and both paid and unpaid bills that span the years 1932-1965. Shop drawings comprises technical drawings for most of the clients mentioned in General Files. Within Design work there is an alphabetical list of the drawings, finished designs and assorted swatches Mr. Guild or his associates used in their work. Photographs contains photographs of many designs of Lurelle Guild's as well as those of other designers. Printed material includes books, magazines, pamphlets, etc. Memorabilia comprises notes, scrapbooks, photographs, books owned by Guild and various other personal items. Models includes serving dishes (of silver, various alloys, and glass), food molds, chairs, coffee pots, and a railroad car.
Material within each series is arranged alphabetically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Industrial Design; Guild, Lurelle.; Industrial design -- United States.; Industrial designers -- United States.; Painters -- United States.; Appointment books.; Bank statements.; Blueprints (reprographic copies); Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Drawings (visual works); Photoprints.; Industrial designers.; Painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- General files
  - A
    - 1933 - 1936 (Box 1)
    - 1936 - 1940 (Box 1)
    - 1942 - 1943 (Box 1)
    - 1944 (Box 1)
    - 1945 (Box 1)
    - 1946 (Box 1)
    - 1950 (Box 1)
  - George Abbott (Box 1)
  - Acosta, J.A. and Company (Box 1)
  - Advertising (Box 1)
  - Alcoa Lawyers' Offices (Box 1)
  - Alcoa - Mrs. Williamson, 1952 - 1953 (Box 1)
  - Alcoa Steamship Company
    - Decorating, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1946, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1947 (Box 1)
    - 1950 (Box 1)
    - 1951 - 1952 (Box 1)
    - 1954, Offices (Box 1)
    - 1954, Worksheets (Box 1)
    - 1954 (Box 1)
    - 1955 (Box 1)
    - 1956, The Tatters (Box 1)
    - 1956, Trinidad (Box 1)
    - 1957, Lt. and Mrs. H. Benton (Box 1)
    - 1957, New Orleans (Box 1)
    - 1956 - 1957 (Box 1)
    - 1958, Contour Chair (Box 1)
    - 1958, Vessels (Box 1)
    - 1957 - 1958, W.C. White (Box 1)
    - 1959 (Box 1)
    - 1960, New York Offices (Box 1)
    - 1965 (Box 1)
  - Allied Chemical Corporation, 1961 - 1963 (Box 2)
  - Aluminum Company of America
    - Al. (Box 2)
    - Fabrics (Box 2)
    - Interiors (Box 2)
    - Newsletter (Box 2)
    - 1/1/35 - 6/30/35 (Box 2)
    - 7/1/35 - 12/31/35 (Box 2)
    - 1/1/36 - [?] (Box 2)
    - 1937 - 1940 (Box 2)
    - 1941 - 1942 (Box 2)
    - 1943 (Box 2)
    - 1944 (Box 2)
    - 1945 (Box 2)
    - 1946 (Box 2)
    - 1948 (Box 2)
    - 1949 (Box 2)
    - 1950 (Box 2)
    - 1951 (Box 2)
    - 1952 - 1953 (Box 2)
  - Aluminum Cooking Utensil Company
    - 1930 - 1932 (Box 2)
    - 1/34 - 6/30/34 (Box 2)
    - 7/1/34 - 12/31/34 (Box 2)
    - 1937 - 1940 (Box 2)
    - 1941 - 1943 (Box 2)
    - 1944 (Box 2)
    - 1945 (Box 2)
    - 1946 (Box 2)
    - 1948 - 1949 (Box 2)
    - 1950 (Box 2)
    - 1951, Offices (Box 2)
    - 1951 (Box 2)
    - 1953, Hallite (Box 2)
    - 1954 (Box 2)
    - 1955 - 1956 (Box 2)
    - 1956 (Box 2)
    - 1957 - 1958 (Box 2)
  - American Airlines, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - American Car and Foundry Company, 1931 - 1932 (Box 3)
  - American Chain and Cable Company, Inc., 1950 (Box 3)
  - American District Telegraph Company, 1938 - [?] (Box 3)
  - American District Telegraph, 1945 (Box 3)
  - American Druggist, 1945 (Box 3)
  - American Hard Rubber Company (Box 3)
  - American Hardware Corporation (Box 3)
  - American Home (Box 3)
  - The American Locomotive Company, 2 folders
    - Duplicates (Box 3)
    - 1931 - 1932 (Box 3)
  - American Machine and Foundry Company, 1962 (Box 3)
  - American Optical Company (Box 3)
  - American Pencil Company (Box 3)
  - American President Lines, 1948 (Box 3)
  - American Pullmatch Corporation, 1 folder
    - Advertising Proofs (Box 3)
    - 1936 (Box 3)
  - American Radiator Company (Box 3)
  - American Railway Car Institute (Box 3)
  - American-Standard, 1948 (Box 3)
  - A.T. and T. - Bell Lab (Box 3)
  - American Television (Box 3)
  - American Thermometer Company (Box 3)
  - Apex Electrical Mfg. Company (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions
    - 1940 - 1943 (Box 3)
    - 1944 - [?] (Box 3)
    - 1945 (Box 3)
    - 1946 (Box 3)
  - Elizabeth Arden, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Arias, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Armstrong Cork and Insulation Company, 1 folder
    - 1957 (Box 3)
    - 1964 (Box 3)
  - Ashbaugh (Box 3)
  - Atwater-Kent Manufacturing Company (Box 3)
  - Automatic Drinking Machine Company (Box 3)
  - Automobile Companies (Box 3)
  - Automobile Manufacturers (Box 3)
  - B
    - 1932 - 1936 (Box 3)
    - 1940 (Box 3)
    - 1940 - 1943 (Box 3)
    - 1944 (Box 3)
    - 1945 (Box 3)
    - 1946 (Box 3)
  - Gil Baird (Box 3)
  - Bakelite Corporation (Box 3)
  - Bank of New York, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Barton Corporation (Box 4)
  - Carl Bartow, Carroll, 1965 - 1966 (Box 4)
  - G.M. Basford Company, 1935 - 1936 (Box 4)
  - Batten, Barton, Durstine and Osborne (Box 4)
  - Beardsley, Wolcott, Manufacturing Company (Box 4)
  - Beaumont, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Becker, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Becker, 1960; 1964 (Box 4)
  - Becton, Dickinson and Company, 1 folder
    - 1938 - [?] (Box 4)
  - Belber Trunk and Bag Company (Box 4)
  - Bell Decorating, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Bellaire Enamel Company (Box 4)
  - Berger Manufacturing Company (Box 4)
  - Bermuda - Discount store, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Bermuda Shoppers' Fair
    - Memos on order, 1962 (Box 4)
    - Notes, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Betts and Betts
    - 1945 (Box 4)
    - 1946 (Box 4)
    - 1948 (Box 4)
    - 1949 (Box 4)
    - 1952, insurance (Box 4)
    - 1958, workmen's compensation and disability benefits (Box 4)
    - 1959 (Box 4)
    - 1951 - 1959, Auto Insurance (Box 4)
    - 1955 - 1961, Connecticut Operation (Box 4)
  - Bigelow, 1 folder
    - 1957, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - F. Billhardt (Box 4)
  - Biographical (Box 4)
  - Bird and Son, Incorporated, 1 folder
    - 1940 - 1943 (Box 4)
  - Bird Floor Covering Survey (Box 4)
  - Birmingham Castleman and Pierce, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Blanchard Brothers and Lane (Box 4)
  - Board of Industrial Counsellors (Box 4)
  - Books (Box 4)
  - Bourjois Inc.
    - 1945 (Box 4)
    - 1946 (Box 4)
    - 1948 (Box 4)
    - 1948 - 1950 (Box 4)
    - 1950 (Box 4)
  - Brearley Company (Box 4)
  - J.G. Brill Company (Box 4)
  - Burgess Battery Company (Box 4)
  - Burke (Box 4)
  - Burwood Products Company (Box 4)
  - Business Advisory Committee of Darien, 1966 (Box 4)
  - C, 1 folder
    - 1932 - 1936 (Box 4)
    - 1940 (Box 4)
    - 1941 - 1943 (Box 5)
    - 1944 (Box 5)
    - 1945 (Box 5)
    - 1946 (Box 5)
  - Cahalane Reg. (Box 5)
  - Carbonic Equipment Corporation (Box 5)
  - The Philip Carey Manufacturing Company
    - 1944 (Box 5)
    - 1945 (Box 5)
    - 1946 - 1957 (Box 5)
  - Carr-Lowry Glass Company (Box 5)
  - Carrier Corporation (Box 5)
  - Convention
    - 1940 - 1943 (Box 5)
    - 1945 - 1946 (Box 5)
    - 1947 (Box 5)
    - 1948 (Box 5)
    - 1949 - 1951 (Box 5)
    - 1952 - 1953 (Box 5)
    - 1954 (Box 5)
    - 1956 - 1957, Monrovia (Box 5)
    - 1956 - 1957, Syracuse (Box 5)
    - 1965 (Box 5)
  - Carrier Engineering Corporation, 1935 - 1936 (Box 5)
  - Carter Brothers, Incorporated (Box 5)
  - Catalina, 1964 (Box 5)
  - Celanese, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Century Silver Company (Box 5)
  - Century Specialty Company, 1936 (Box 5)
  - Chase Brass and Copper Company
    - Comments on Catalogue (Box 5)
    - 9/28/32 - 12/30/33 (Box 5)
    - 1/1/34 - 6/25/34 (Box 5)
    - 6/25/34 - 12/31/34 (Box 5)
    - 1/1/35 - [?] (Box 5)
  - Chase National Bank (Box 5)
  - Chesebrough Ponds (Box 5)
  - Christmas List (Box 5)
  - C.F. Church Manufacturing Company, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - E.K. Clark Residence, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Clients
    - 1945 (Box 5)
    - 1952 - 1953 (Box 5)
  - Clippings of interest
    - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - 1945 (Box 5)
  - Colgate Palmolive Company, 1 folder
    - 1957 - 1959, 1963 - 1964 (Box 5)
  - Colliers, 1946 (Box 5)
  - Compton Advertising, Inc.
    - 1938 - 1942 (Box 5)
    - 1944 (Box 5)
  - Condé Nast Publications, Inc. (Box 5)
  - Congoleum - Nairn (Box 5)
  - "Congratulations" etc. (Box 5)
  - Conlon Corporation (Box 5)
  - "Contracts", 1944 (Box 5)
  - Contracts, 1945 (Box 5)
  - Corcoran - Brown Lamp Company (Box 5)
  - Corning Glass Works, 2 folders
    - 1939 - 1942 (Box 5)
  - Corry - Jamestown (Box 6)
  - Cort Cosmetics, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Cory Corporation, 1948 - 1949 (Box 6)
  - Coty, 1956 - 1957 (Box 6)
  - Nancy Craig, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Crowell Publishing Company (Box 6)
  - Crown - Underwood (Box 6)
  - D
    - 1935 (Box 6)
    - 1939 - 1940 (Box 6)
    - 1941 - 1943 (Box 6)
    - 1944 (Box 6)
    - 1945 (Box 6)
    - 1951 (Box 6)
  - Dale Decorators, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Darien - Civics (Box 6)
  - Desk stamp pads, 1949 - 1951 (Box 6)
  - Development work (Box 6)
  - R.E. Dietz Company, 1939 - 1941 (Box 6)
  - Dixie Cup Company
    - 1944 (Box 6)
    - 1945 (Box 6)
    - 1946 (Box 6)
  - Doane Products Corporation (Box 6)
  - Dominion Oilcloth and Linoleum Company, Ltd. (Box 6)
  - Doubleday - Doran Company (Box 6)
  - Dow Corning (Chemical), 1960 (Box 6)
  - Drapery, 1958 (Box 6)
  - Dunn - J. Frank, 1961 (Box 6)
  - E.I. DuPont De Nemours and Company, 3 folders
    - 1945 (Box 6)
  - Dutch Treat Club, 1959 (Box 6)
  - E
    - 1935 - 1936 (Box 6)
    - 1937 - 1940 (Box 6)
    - 1944 (Box 6)
    - 1945 (Box 6)
  - Eastern Airlines, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Thomas A. Edison Inc. (Box 6)
  - Edison Wood Products, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Edwards and Company, 2 folders
    - 1945 (Box 6)
    - 1948 - 1954 (Box 6)
  - ELAP, 1958 (Box 6)
  - Elastic Stop Nut Corporation
    - Advertising Data (Box 6)
    - Leather Samples (Box 6)
    - 1941 - 1942 (Box 6)
    - 1943, Jan. to June (Box 6)
    - 1944 (Box 6)
    - 1945 (Box 6)
    - 1946 (Box 6)
    - Electric Railway President's Conference Committee (Box 6)
    - Electric Manufacturing, 1935 - 1937 (Box 6)
    - Electrolux Corporation (Box 6)
    - 1934 - 1943 (Box 6)
    - 1944 (Box 6)
    - 1945 (Box 6)
    - 1948 (Box 6)
    - 1949 (Box 6)
    - 1954 (Box 7)
    - 1959, Interiors (Box 7)
    - 1961 - 1963 (Box 7)
    - 1964, Beauty Center (Box 7)
  - F
    - 1935 - 1936 (Box 7)
    - 1937 - 1939 (Box 7)
    - 1941 - 1943 (Box 7)
    - 1944 (Box 7)
    - 1945 (Box 7)
    - 1946 (Box 7)
  - F. and N. Lawn Mower Company, 1944 (Box 7)
  - Federal Housing Authority, 1942 - 1943 (Box 7)
  - Fiberglas, 1953 - 1956 (Box 7)
  - Fiberglas, 1957 (Box 7)
  - George T. Fielding, 1941 - 1943 (Box 7)
  - George T. Fielding, 1944 - 1945 (Box 7)
  - Fifth Avenue Bank, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Fitzgerald Manufacturing Company (Box 7)
  - Follow (Box 7)
  - Foreign Fairs and Exhibits, 1957 (Box 7)
  - Foreign Operations Administration (Box 7)
  - Fostoria Glass Company (Box 7)
  - Fram Corporation
    - 1943 (Box 7)
    - 1944 (Box 7)
    - 1945 (Box 7)
  - Frigidaire Corporation (Box 7)
  - Fuller and Smith and Ross Inc., 1934; 1936 (Box 7)
  - Fuller and Smith and Ross Inc., 1957 - 1961 (Box 7)
  - G
    - 1932 - 1936 (Box 7)
    - 1937 - 1940, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - 1941 - 1943 (Box 7)
    - 1944 (Box 7)
    - 1945 (Box 7)
    - 1946 (Box 7)
  - Gardening (Box 7)
  - Garton Toy Company (Box 7)
  - General Electric Company, 1931; 1936 (Box 7)
  - General Electric Company, 1937 - 1940 (Box 7)
  - General Fireproofing Company, 1 folder
    - 1956 (Box 7)
  - General Foods
    - 1948 (Box 7)
    - 1949 (Box 7)
    - 1953 (Box 7)
  - General Motors Truck Corporation (Box 7)
  - General Plastics (Box 7)
  - General Thrift, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Geiringer (Box 7)
  - Geroter May Corporation, 1946 (Box 7)
  - Geyer Advertising, 1958 (Box 7)
  - Geyer Company, Inc. (Box 7)
  - A.C. Gilbert Company (Box 7)
  - Gleason - Tiebout Glass Company (Box 7)
  - Goblin Electric Cleaner, 1943 (Box 7)
  - Goblin Electric Cleaner, 1944 - 1945 (Box 7)
  - Gold Medal Folding Furniture Co. (Box 7)
  - The B. F. Goodrich Rubber Co. (Box 7)
  - W.A. Gough, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Grable, 1 folder
    - 1955 - 1956, 1 folder (Box 8)
    - Confidential (Box 8)
    - 1957 - 1959 (Box 8)
    - 1959 (Box 8)
  - Graham Washer, 1945 (Box 8)
  - A.H. Grebe and Co., Inc. (Box 8)
  - Greif (Box 8)
  - Grinnell Washing Machine Corp. (Box 8)
  - Griswold Manufacturing Company (Box 8)
  - Grocery Food Stores (Box 8)
  - Lurelle Guild Associates, 1 folder
    - Broadcast (Box 8)
    - Income Tax
      - 1945 (Box 8)
      - 1946 (Box 8)
    - Insurance (Box 8)
    - Insurance and Compensation
      - 1946 (Box 8)
      - 1948 (Box 8)
      - 1949 (Box 8)
      - 1950 (Box 8)
    - Office lease (Box 8)
    - Research, 1941 (Box 8)
    - Surveys and reports (Box 8)
  - Guild Personal, 2 folders
    - Advertising, publicity (Box 8)
    - Photos (Box 8)
    - Plays (Box 8)
    - Talks, speeches, etc. (Box 8)
    - Writings, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Writings (oversize), misc. (Oversize 1)
    - 1942 (Box 8)
    - 1943 (Box 8)
    - 1944, Speeches (Box 8)
    - 1944 (Box 8)
    - 1945, Publicity (Box 8)
    - 1945, Speeches (Box 8)
    - 1944 - 1945 (Box 8)
    - 1946, Publicity (Box 8)
    - 1946, Xmas thank you notes (Box 8)
    - 1946 (Box 8)
    - 1948 (Box 9)
    - 1949 (Box 9)
    - 1950 (Box 9)
    - 1951 - 1953 (Box 9)
    - 1954 - 1955 (Box 9)
  - Gulf Oil Corporation
    - 1937 (Box 9)
    - 1938 (Box 9)
    - 1939 (Box 9)
    - 1940 (Box 9)
    - 1941 (Box 9)
    - 1943 (Box 9)
    - 1944 (Box 9)
  - Gypsum Wall Board (Box 9)
  - H
    - 1935 - 1936 (Box 9)
    - 1941 - 1943 (Box 9)
    - 1944 (Box 9)
    - 1945 (Box 9)
    - 1946 (Box 9)
  - Hamilton Autographic Register Company (Box 9)
  - Hamilton Beach Manufacturing Company (Box 9)
  - Hamilton Manufacturing Company (Box 9)
  - Hartmann Trunk Company (Box 9)
  - Heinz, H.J. - Company (Box 9)
  - Heminway, 1961 (Box 9)
  - Andrew B. Hendryx Company (Box 9)
  - Henjes / McPhee (Box 9)
  - G. F. Heublein and Brothers, 1935 - 1936 (Box 9)
  - Hewitt - Robins, 1956 (Box 9)
  - Heywood - Wakefield, 1959 (Box 9)
  - Hinshaw, 1956 (Box 9)
  - Hoegger Incorporated (Box 9)
  - Holcomb and Hoke Manufacturing Company, 1942 - 1944 (Box 9)
  - Horton Manufacturing Company (Box 9)
  - Howard Johnson, 1959 - 1960 (Box 9)
  - Hurley Machine Company, 1931 - 1936 (Box 9)
  - Hyland and Gregory, 1936 - 1939 (Box 9)
  - Hyland and Gregory, 1941 - 1943 (Box 9)
  - I
    - 1932 - 1936 (Box 9)
    - 1941 - 1943 (Box 9)
    - 1944 (Box 9)
    - 1945 (Box 9)
  - Imperial Paper and Color Corporation, 1 folder
    - 1933 - 1936 (Box 9)
  - Industrial Design, 1959 (Box 9)
  - Industrial Designers Society of America (Box 9)
  - Ingersoll - Waterbury Company (Box 9)
  - Insurance and Compensation, 1941 - 1943 (Box 9)
  - Insurance and Compensation, 1945 (Box 9)
  - International Business Machines Corporation, 1 folder
    - 1956 - 1957 (Box 9)
  - International Cooperation Administration (Box 9)
  - International Nickel, 1964 (Box 9)
  - International Silver Company, 2 folders
    - 1955 (Box 9)
  - International Silver Duplicates (Box 9)
  - International Trade Fairs, 1956 (Box 9)
  - J
    - 1935 - 1936 (Box 9)
    - 1941 - 1943 (Box 9)
    - 1944 (Box 9)
    - 1945 (Box 9)
  - Jensen, Andrew and Company (Box 9)
  - Jewett Refrigerator Company, Inc.
    - 1943 (Box 9)
    - 1944 (Box 9)
    - 1945 (Box 9)
  - Johns - Manville
    - 1933 - 1936 (Box 9)
    - 1936 - 1940 (Box 9)
    - 1943 (Box 9)
    - 1945 - 1946 (Box 9)
    - 1950 (Box 10)
    - 1957 (Box 10)
  - Judd, H. L. Company, 1931 (Box 10)
  - K
    - 1937 - 1940 (Box 10)
    - 1942 - 1943 (Box 10)
    - 1944 (Box 10)
    - 1946 (Box 10)
  - Joseph A. Kaplan, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Kaufman - Strouse (Box 10)
  - Kaufman, Subotnik, Chessler, Inc., 1966 (Box 10)
  - Julius Kayser and Company
    - 1946 (Box 10)
  - Kensington Incorporated, 2 folders
    - Correspondence on and Suggestions for New Items (Box 10)
    - Market Surveys (Box 10)
    - Showroom Job (Box 10)
    - Telegrams (Box 10)
    - 1/1/35 - 7/31/35 (Box 10)
    - 8/1/35 - 12/31/35 (Box 10)
    - 1936 (Box 10)
    - 1/1/36 - 12/31/36 (Box 10)
    - 1937 (Box 10)
    - 1938 (Box 10)
    - 1939 (Box 10)
    - 1936 - 1939, Advertising Material (Box 10)
    - 1937 - 1939, Patent Papers and Letters (Box 10)
    - 1940, Salesmen Reports and Suggestions (Box 10)
    - 1940 (Box 10)
    - 1941, Correspondence (Box 10)
    - 1942 (Box 10)
    - 1943 (Box 10)
    - 1941 - 1943, Salesmen Reports and Suggestions (Box 10)
    - 1944 (Box 10)
    - 1945 (Box 10)
    - 1946 (Box 10)
    - 1947 (Box 10)
    - 1948 (Box 10)
    - 1949 (Box 11)
    - 1950 (Box 11)
    - 1951 - 1953 (Box 11)
    - 1954 (Box 11)
    - 1956 (Box 11)
    - 1957 - 1958 (Box 11)
    - 1959 - 1960 (Box 11)
  - Ketchum, MacLeod, and Grove, Inc., 1957 (Box 11)
  - Kittinger Company, 1933 - 1936 (Box 11)
  - Kohler Company, 1931 - 1932 (Box 11)
  - Krimko Company (Box 11)
  - Kroehler Manufacturing Company
    - 1943 (Box 11)
    - 1944 (Box 11)
    - 1945 (Box 11)
    - 1963, Props for Room Settings (Box 11)
    - 1963, Royalties (Box 11)
    - 1961 - 1965 (Box 11)
  - Kullber, 1957 - 1958 (Box 11)
  - L
    - 1934 - 1936 (Box 11)
    - 1937 - 1940 (Box 11)
    - 1942 - 1943 (Box 11)
    - 1944 - 1945 (Box 11)
  - Jane Pickens Longley, 1964 (Box 11)
  - Lever Brothers, 1962 - 1965 (Box 11)
  - Lever Brothers, 1964 (Box 11)
  - Lorell Manufacturing Company, 1933 - 1935 (Box 11)
  - Lofgren Furniture, 1957 - 1958; 1960 - 1963 (Box 11)
  - Lyons Metal, 1942 - 1943 (Box 11)
  - M
    - 1934 - 1936 (Box 11)
    - 1937 - 1940 (Box 11)
    - 1941 - 1943 (Box 11)
    - 1944 (Box 11)
    - 1945 (Box 11)
    - 1946 (Box 11)
  - Mc, 1944 (Box 11)
  - McCarthy, 1958 (Box 11)
  - Macey - Fowler, 1950 - 1951 (Box 11)
  - McKee Glass Company (Box 11)
  - Marine Museum, 1951 (Box 11)
  - Maryland Distilleries, Inc., 1934 - 1935 (Box 11)
  - Maryl and Distilling (Box 11)
  - May Oil Burner Corporation, 1 folder
    - 1939 - 1940 (Box 11)
    - 1941 (Box 11)
    - 1942 (Box 11)
    - 1943 (Box 11)
    - 1944 (Box 11)
    - 1945 (Box 11)
  - Maytag Company (Box 11)
  - Mengel Body Company (Box 11)
  - Milestone Village (Box 11)
  - Miller Metal Products, 1943 - 1944 (Box 11)
  - Miller Metal Products, 1945 - 1946 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1 folder
    - 1935 - 1940 (Box 12)
    - 1937 - 1939 (Box 12)
    - 1952 (Box 12)
    - 1954 (Box 12)
    - 1959 - 1965 (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous information (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous story material (Box 12)
  - Margaret Mitchell House, 1955 (Box 12)
  - Modine Manufacturing Company, 1933 - 1934 (Box 12)
  - Mohasco Industries, 1962 - 1965 (Box 12)
  - Mohawk Carpet Mills, Inc.
    - 1933 - 1938 (Box 12)
    - 1939 - 1940 (Box 12)
    - 1940 (Box 12)
    - 1941 - 1942 (Box 12)
    - 1943 (Box 12)
    - 1944 (Box 12)
    - 1945 (Box 12)
    - 1946 (Box 12)
    - 1947 (Box 12)
    - 1948 (Box 12)
    - 1949 (Box 12)
    - 1950 (Box 12)
    - 1951 - 1953 (Box 12)
    - 1954 (Box 12)
  - Monsanto Chemical Company, 1938 - 1940 (Box 13)
  - Monsanto Chemical Company, 1941 (Box 13)
  - Montgomery Ward (Box 13)
  - Moran, 1966 (Box 13)
  - A.R. Morrow, 1951 - 1952 (Box 13)
  - Moser and Cotins, 1938 - 1939 (Box 13)
  - Moser and Cotins, 1941 (Box 13)
  - Mott, George M., 1960 (Box 13)
  - Mueller (Box 13)
  - Mullan Company, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Murray (Box 13)
  - Murray Corporation of America, 1950 (Box 13)
  - Mus - Amp, 1965 (Box 13)
  - N
    - 1933 - 1936 (Box 13)
    - 1938 - 1940 (Box 13)
    - 1941 - 1943 (Box 13)
    - 1944 (Box 13)
    - 1945 (Box 13)
  - Nassau County Historical Museum, 1966 (Box 13)
  - National Alliance of Art and Industry, 1932 - 1936 (Box 13)
  - National Enameling and Stamping Company, 1932 - 1936 (Box 13)
  - National Radiator Company, 1934 - 1936 (Box 13)
  - National Radiator Company, 1935 - 1939 (Box 13)
  - National Stamping and Electric Works (Box 13)
  - National - U.S. Radiator, 1956 (Box 13)